Finding Aid for the Thompson-Boling Arena Construction Photographs AR.0803
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
Thompson-Boling Arena Construction Photographs
1984-1986
AR.0803
University of Tennessee Libraries, Special Collections
3.75 Linear feet
The Thompson-Boling arena construction photograph collection houses the photographs that were taken during the planning, construction, and finalization of Thompson-Boling Arena. The Thompson-boling Arena, home to the University of Tennessee's men's and women's basketball teams and the Lady Volunteer volleyball team, was first put in use during the 1987-88 sports season after its construction.
University of Tennessee, Knoxville. Facilities Services.
Biographical/Historical Note
The Thompson-Boling arena is named for B. Ray Thompson, Tennessee coal magnate and patron of the arena, and former U.T. president Dr. Edward J. Boling. The construction of the arena and the images from the collection span from early stages of development in 1983 to the finalization of the structure in 1987. Currently, with both the Tennessee Volunteers and Lady Volunteers basketball teams consistently in the top 25, Thompson–Boling Arena has received much attention as a premier college basketball facility. In addition, when UT sports are out of season, events and concerts are held in the arena.
Conditions Governing Access
Colletions are stored offsite, and a minimum of 24 hours is needed to retrieve these items for use. Researchers interested in consulting any of the collections are advised to contact Special Collections at special@utk.edu.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection of Thompson-Boling arena construction photographs has been divided into three series.
The first series of photographs appear on slides, with two slides corresponding to every workday until October 8, 1985. Series one is comprised of the the beginning documentation of arena construction, and is organized on a monthly basis.
Series two is comprised of mixed black-and-white photographs and color slides from October 8, 1985 to December 31, 1986. Series two marks increased frequency and volume of captured images and slides. Series two is organized by day since photographs and slides regularly occur in large quantities on a daily basis.
Series three houses color proofs that depict the final stages of construction from April 1987 to December 1987. Proofs of series three include up to eight photographs on each page, all organized sequentially by the areas photographed.
Subjects
University of Tennessee, Knoxville.; University of Tennessee, Knoxville -- Buildings.; University of Tennessee, Knoxville -- History.
Container List
- Early Stages of Construction Slides, 1983 November 1 - 1985 September 18
  Scope and Contents Note
  Slides from the initiation of the construction of Thompson-Boling Arena. Two slides are regularly timestamped for each day that images were captured.
  - Slides, 1983 November (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Slides, 1983 December (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Slides, 1984 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Slides, 1984 February (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Slides, 1984 March (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Slides, 1984 April (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Slides, 1984 May (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Slides, 1984 June (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Slides, 1984 July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Slides, 1984 August (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Slides, 1984 September (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Slides, 1984 October (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Slides, 1984 November (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Slides, 1984 December (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Slides, 1985 January (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Slides, 1985 February (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Slides, 1985 March (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Slides, 1985 April (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Slides, 1985 May (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Slides, 1985 June (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Slides, 1985 July (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Slides, 1985 August (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Slides, 1985 September (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Middle Stages of Construction Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 8 - 1986 December 31
  Photographs and Slides occur on regular weekdays in instances of four images or more captured every work day. Mixed slides and photographs; some photographs from this series were excluded due to water damage.
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 8 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 28 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 1 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 14 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 15 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 22 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 December 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 December 4 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1985 December 6 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 6 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 7 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 8 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 9 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 13 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 14 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 15 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 16 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 17 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 21 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 22 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 23 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 27 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 January 31 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 3 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 4 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 5 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 7 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 10 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 11 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 12 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 13 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 18 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 20 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 24 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 25 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 26 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 27 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 February 28 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 3 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 5 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 10 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 11 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 12 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 13 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 21 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 24 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 25 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 27 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 March 31 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 4 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 7 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 8 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 11 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 14 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 15 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 17 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 April 18 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 May 8 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 23 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 28 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 29 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 July 30 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 1 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 4 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 5 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 6 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 8 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 11 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 12 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 13 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 15 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 20 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 21 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 22 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 25 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 26 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 27 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 August 29 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 3 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 4 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 5 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 8 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 9 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 10 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 15 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 19 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 22 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 23 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 24 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 25 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 29 (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 September 30 (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 1 (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 2 (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 3 (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 7 (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 10 (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 28 (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 29 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 October 30 (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 3 (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 6 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 10 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 12 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 13 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 14 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 17 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 19 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 21 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 November 26 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 2 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 5 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 16 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 17 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 18 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 19 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 29 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 30 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Slides and Photographs, 1986 December 31 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Final Stages of Construction Proofs, 1987 April - 1987 December
  Photograph proofs of the final stages of construction. Photo proofs are collated sequentially.
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 April (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 May (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 June (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 July (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 August (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 September (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 October (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 November (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Photograph Proofs, 1987 December (Box 5, Folder 9)